A Guide to the Papers of the Twin Oaks Community 1969-1987
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Twin Oaks Community 1969-1987
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9840-q
This collection consists of ca. 1300 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access is restricted to those having the written permission of the Twin Oaks Community Board of Planners.
Acquisition Information
This material was placed on loan with the Library by the Twin Oaks Community Board of Planners through Mary Lou LeClair, Twin Oaks Archives, Louisa, Virginia, on December 12, 1990.
Biographical/Historical Information
Twin Oaks is a collective settlement established in 1967 in Louisa County, Va., inspired by B.F. Skinner's "Walden Two."
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of personal and business correspondence and papers, business and legal documents, manuscripts, agenda and minutes, and videotapes pertaining to various aspects of the Twin Oaks Community.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Councils
  - Agriculture Council 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Child Council 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Child Council 1971-1974 (Box 1)
    Meta Meeting Notes
  - Child Council 1975 (Box 1)
  - Child Council 1976-1979, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Construction and Utilities Council 1973-1981 (Box 2)
  - Construction and Utilities Council 1977-1979 (Box 2)
    Meeting Notes
  - Culinary Council 1975-1981 (Box 2)
  - Domestic Council 1975-1981 (Box 2)
  - Domestic Council 1978-1981 (Box 2)
    (Small Living Groups) SLG Board
  - HEW Council 1976-1981 (Box 2)
  - Income Council 1981 (Box 2)
    Indexing--Business Set-up
  - Income Council 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    Outside Work
  - Income Council 1978-1981 (Box 3)
    Products--Emerald City
  - Income Council 1971-1981, 2 folders (Box 3)
    Products--Hammocks
  - Income Council 1977-1981 (Box 3)
    Products--Hammocks Management and Business
  - Income Council 1977-1979 (Box 3)
    Products--Hammocks Production Incentive Program
  - Income Council 1972-1975 (Box 3)
    Products--Stretcher Making
  - Income Council 1976 (Box 3)
    Small Business Council
  - Office Council 1972-1981 (Box 3)
  - Outreach Council 1971-1981, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Outreach Council 1977-1981 (Box 4)
    East Wind Community
  - Outreach Council 1971-1974 (Box 4)
    A Walden Two Experiment... by Kathleen Kinkade
  - Planning Council 1969-1981 (Box 4)
    Community Planners
  - Planning Council 1974-1975 (Box 4)
    Community Planners--Business Meeting Notes
  - Planning Council 1976 (Box 4)
  - Planning Council 1977 (Box 5)
  - Planning Coucil 1977 (Box 5)
    Community Planners--Informants and Decisions
  - Planning Council 1975-1979, 2 folders (Box 5)
    Economic Planning
  - Planning Council 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Planning Council 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    Juniper Planner Meeting Notes
  - Planning Council 1975-1981 (Box 6)
    Labor
  - Planning Council 1971-1981 (Box 6)
    Land Planning
  - Planning Council 1969-1981 (Box 6)
    Legal
  - Planning Council 1975-1981 (Box 6)
    Local Relations
  - Planning Council 1976-1978 (Box 7)
  - Planning Council 1975-1981 (Box 7)
    Membership Team
  - Planning Council 1977-1981 (Box 7)
    Taxes
  - Support Council 1973-1981 (Box 7)
  - Transportation and Maintenance Council 1979-1981 (Box 7)
- Values 1973-1981 (Box 7)
- Controversial Issues
  - Branch Development 1972-1979 (Box 7)
  - Farm Crisis 1978-1981 (Box 7)
  - Personal Money Issues 1977-1981 (Box 7)
- Videotapes
  - Twin Oaks Community ca. 1973-1976
    - "New Age Communities, A Search for Utopia" n.d. (Reel 1)
    - "Window on the World" n.d. (Reel 2)
    - Home movies Mid-1970s (Reel 3)
    - "Grass Roots--Rural Communes in the USA" n.d. (Reel 4)
    - "Take 30" n.d. (Reel 5)
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11)
    20th Anniversary, Peter Sugarman--Win--Day 2
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 12, 13, 14, 15 ,16, 17)
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23)
    20th Anniversary, Peter Sugarman--Bill--Day 3
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29)
    20th Anniversary, Peter Sugarman--Bill--Day 4
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29)
    20th Anniversary, Peter Sugarman--Win--Days 3 & 4
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35)
    20th Anniversary, Peter Sugarman
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35)
    20th Anniversary, Peter Sugarman--Win
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 36, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41)
    20th Anniversary, Peter Sugarman--Bill
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 36, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41)
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 42, 43, 44, 45, 46, 47)
  - Twin Oaks Community 1987 June (Reel 42, 43, 44, 45, 46 ,47)